迈克:啊…布鲁沃尔先生.
Mike: Ah... Mr.Brower.
卢克:抱歉,我迟到了,西沃老师.
Luke: Sorry I'm late Mr.Seaver
迈克:卢克,你连续迟到三次了.
Mike: That's the third time in a row Luke,
也许我该打555电话让他们早上叫醒你.
maybe I should call 555-Deli and leave a wake up call?
卢克:别担心,我只在课堂上睡觉.
Luke: Don't worry I only sleep in class
迈克:喂,熟食店吗?我是佛兰西斯泰德斯科.请找一下你们的一个雇员,叫卢克布鲁沃尔.
Mike: Hello, So ho Pete's?This is Francis X Tedesco and I need to speak with one of your employees Luke Brower
他是个伙计,也许是个干杂活的.你肯定?好的,谢谢你.真怪,他们没听说过他.
I think he's a waiter, well maybe a bus boy.You sure?Ok thank you.That's funny they never heard of him.
泰德斯科先生:我们也是.我曾想调阅他的档案,却没找到.
Mr.Tedesco: Neither have we, I just tried to pull his file, there isn't one.
迈克:档案丢了吗?
Mike: His file is missing?
泰德斯科先生:不是,卢克布鲁沃尔根本不存在.
Mr.Tedesco: No, Luke Brower does not exist.
迈克:谢谢.卢克,我不信你在那里住.
Mike: Thank you.Luke I can't believe you're living here.
卢克:是吗,就在那里啊.
Luke: Well, I am.
迈克:你把我整糊涂了.你爸妈呢??
Mike: Well I don't get it, what about your parents!??
卢克:我没有,也不需要什么爸妈.我在这里很好.
Luke: I don't have any and I don't need them.I am doing fine right here.
迈克:卢克,就没有比这更好的地方了吗!!??
Mike: Luke, there's got to be some place better than this!!??
卢克:是啊,是啊,还有哪里?
Luke: Yeah Yeah, Like where?
迈克:还有,还有,比方说城市郊区的某个舒适的地方.
Mike: Like Like, some sort of city outreach sort of nice, happy place!!??
卢克:我都去过了.还是这里好.
Luke: I've tried all the happy places, this is better.
迈克:这里住着一个无家可归的孩子!!!
Mike: We have a homeless boy living here!!!
泰德斯科先生:什么!!??这是学校.孩子怎么能住这里!!!我要叫儿童福利院的人过来.
Mr.Tedesco: What!!??This is a school, we can't have kids here!!!I'll call the bureau of child welfare.
迈克:我不会让你这样流落街头的!!
Mike: I can't let you live on a street like this!!
卢克:你不会吗?今天早上我没有流落街头,
Luke: Oh you can't let me!!??Well this morning I wasn't on the street.
我有睡的地方,有吃的地方,而且有读书的地方.
I had a place to sleep and a place to eat and a promising academic career.
而现在呢?就因为你,我真成了无家可归,饥寒交迫的人了.你算老几?查尔斯凯丁这样的警察?
Now thanks to you I'm a homeless hungry dropout.Who are you?Charles Keeting!
卢克:你肯定没问题吗?
Luke: Are you sure this is ok?
迈克:是,是,
Mike: Yeah yeah, you can sleep in my sister's room.
你可以睡在我妹妹的房间里.别担心,没关系的.
Don't worry it's fine she's away at college and you can talk to my dad
她一直在学校里住.明天你再跟我爸爸聊聊.
in the morning.
卢克:我听你的.
Luke: I don't know,.
迈克:别担心,这很好.你上楼去,
Mike: Stop worrying, it's fine just go on upstairs,
右边第一个房间.呃…对了,有时她在床上会放个呃…
first door on the right and uhh... Sometimes she keeps this umm...
大绒毛玩具狗.拿开它,上床就行了.
big stuffed dog on her bed just shove it off and hop in.
卡罗尔:啊!!!
Carol: Ah!!
迈克:嘿,卢克!你脖子还疼吗?
Mike: Oh Luke!Is your neck still bothering you?
听着,你可以不睡地板的,你有水床啊.
Oh Listen, you shouldn't have slept on the floor, you had the water bed.
卢克:我可不想睡在那上面,会弄湿我的.
Luke: Nah I didn't want to sleep in a bed that might wet me.
迈克:如果我给你做一顿最好吃的迈克尔西沃极品自制早餐,你会听我的吗?
Mike: What do you say I make up for it with one of Michael Seaver's
super duper homemade breakfasts
卢克:好极了!
Luke: Great!
迈克:那好!你是喜欢果味脆片还是"斯马奇"花生排?
Mike: Ok!What do we have marshmallow Twinkle or Mr.Smackie's Peanut Logs?
卢克:我好是喜欢来点热的.
Luke: Well I was kind of hoping for something hot.
迈克:你可以饱餐一顿花生排,但得小心别把你的嘴烫着.
Mike: Well you can heat up with peanut logs but they'll burn the roof
好吧,我给你做点去.
of your mouth.Ok I'll cook something.
卢克:再来点薄烤饼好吗?
Luke: How about pancakes?
迈克:好的.我们出去.
Mike: Ok, we'll go out.
卢克:你这里真是应有尽有啊:面粉,油,还有鸡蛋.
Luke: Well you got everything you need right here: flour, oil and eggs.
迈克:喔,你是怎么学会做这个的?
Mike: Wow, how did you learn how to make pancakes?
卢克:10岁以前,我一直帮着妈妈在俄勒冈州的一个伐木场做饭.
Luke: Till I was ten years old I used to help my mother cook at
a lumber camp in Oregon
迈克:真的?
Mike: Really?
卢克:对啊!跟68个手握电锯的工人在一起,你最好什么都会干点.
Luke: Yep!When you got 68 men with chainsaws you better learn to watch you fly boy.
迈克:嘿,卢克,为什么不在我家多待些日子呢?
Mike: Listen Luke, why don't you just stay here for a while?
卢克:什么?
Luke: Huh?
迈克:你被赶到大街上,还有别的事,这多少是我的错.
Mike: Well you being out on the street and everything, it's kind of my fault.
卢克:我可没这么说…
Luke: Well I wouldn't say that...
迈克:真的!?
Mike: Really!?
卢克:这完全是你的错.
Luke: It's totally your fault,
可你父母不会让我赖在这里的.
but there's no way your parents will ever let me stay here.
迈克:我父母!!?卢克,卢克,卢克,
Mike: My parents!!?Luke Luke Luke, see this?
看这个.他们全听这根手指的,我还有9根作备用呢.
This is the finger I have them wrapped around and I got nine more on standby.
如果我说让你留下,那你留定了.
If I say you're staying, your staying.
玛吉:不管你说什么,他不能留下.
Maggie: I don't care what you say, he's not staying.
迈克:但是,为什么!!??
Mike: But, why!!??
玛吉:迈克,这不像是带回一只流浪狗.
Maggie: Mike, this isn't like bringing home a stray puppy.
这个卢克可能很危险.他可能是个贼,
This Luke could be dangerous,
而且家里还有个妹妹呢.
he could be a thief and we do have a five year old.
贾森:你妈妈说的对.迈克,我们得为克里西着想.
Jason: Your mom has a point Mike, we've got to think of Chrissy.
迈克:妈妈,他不危险,他是我最优秀的学生!
Mike: Mom, he's not dangerous, he's my best student!
而且他从不偷东西,除了食物,衣服以及有线电视.
Ok and he's never stolen a thing except for food, clothes and home box office.
贾森:迈克,我们的意思是…你说他偷了有线电视??
Jason: Mike all we're saying is....He gets cable for free!??
玛吉:贾森,别岔开.迈克,你没这个权利!
Maggie: Jason stay focused.Mike you have no right!
迈克:妈妈,我觉得你太自私了.
Mike: Mom, I think you are being selfish.
玛吉:自私!!??是你太天真了.
Maggie: Selfish!!??You're being na?ve.
贾森:迈克,玛吉,冷静点.我们一起冷静地分析一下.
Jason: Mike, Maggie, wait a minute.Let's keep our emotions in check here.
卡罗尔:迈克你这个笨蛋,在你所做的无数蠢事中,
Carol: Mike you slime bucket, of all the dumb things you've done,
这算的上是登峰造极了.
this is the dumbest.
本:完全正确.
Ben: Give it to him!
卡罗尔:首先,你把一个陌生人带进我们家.
Carol: First you bring a complete stranger into our house.
本:你的床.
Ben: Your bed.
卡罗尔:然后你让他睡到我床上.
Carol: And then you send him into my bed.
本:霸占了.
Ben: Occupied.
卡罗尔:对啊!趁着我料理那些可恶的功课的时候!
Carol: That's right!Why I'm minding my own stinking business!
本:老姐,说的好.
Ben: Bring it home baby.
卡罗尔:你干的这件事实在是低级,无耻,
Carol: What you have done is so low and despicable that even your apprentice
连你的这个笨蛋徒弟都附和我.
slime ball here agrees with me.
本:不,我没有.
Ben: No I don't.
卡罗尔:你没有?那你一上午老顺着我的话说是为什么?
Carol: You don't?Then why have you been agreeing with me all morning?
本:我只是希望看到你大发雷霆,
Ben: I just want to see you get so mad that you flick foam from the
弄的满嘴白沫乱飞.
corners of your mouth.
卡罗尔:你这毒蛇!你这小破孩!你这狡猾的小坏蛋!
Carol: You snake!You scuzzwad!You slimy sniggley slime bucket!
本:别动!没错!成功了,她真的满嘴白沫.
Ben: There it is!Yes!Mission control we have achieved foam!
贾森:别折磨你姐姐了.卡罗尔,擦擦你的嘴.
Jason: Stop torturing your sister.Carol wipe your mouth.
卡罗尔:妈妈,爸爸,我要求开家庭会议.
Carol: Mom, Dad, I demand a family conference.
玛吉:卡罗尔,这个主意很棒.
Maggie: Carol that is an excellent suggestion.
你和本可以出去一下吗?
Would you and Ben please leave the room?
卡罗尔:但这是我的主意啊!!??
Carol: But it was my idea!!??
贾森:对,这个主意不错,宝贝.现在你出去!
Jason: Yes it was a good one sweetheart, now get out!
迈克,玛吉,
Ok Mike, Maggie, I think we owe Mike a chance to explain himself before
我想在武断拒绝之前,该给迈克一个自我辩护的机会.
we give him our arbitrary refusal.
迈克:谢谢爸爸!
Mike: Thank you!
玛吉:好吧.
Maggie: Alright.
迈克:卢克现在能留下!?
Mike: Now can Luke stay!?
玛吉:不可能.
Maggie: No Chance.
迈克:爸爸!
Mike: Dad!
贾森:等一下,你母亲的意思是我们理解卢克是个穷孩子.
Jason: Wait wait, what your mother is saying is we realize that Luke is a needy guy.
迈克:是的!
Mike: Yes!
贾森:我们也有能力帮助他,而且卡罗尔搬到宿舍去住了,
Jason: And yes we do have a lot to share and yes carol is off to
家里多出一个房间.那么问题是什么,玛吉?
her dorm so we do have an extra room.What was the problem Maggie?
玛吉:贾森,他不能留下来.
Maggie: Jason he can't stay here.
Mike: Ok Fine!Can't stay here锛寃here锛?
迈克:那好吧!不留下来,让他到哪里去?
贾森:收养家庭.我一直给儿童福利院做咨询.
Jason: Foster home, I've consulted the bureau of child welfare Mike,
迈克,我可以帮他找个好人家,不过得花点时间.
I can help him get a great one, it will just take a little time.
这期间,他可以住到一个叫帕顿霍尔的救济机构里去,
Meanwhile he can stay at a facility called Paton Hall,
当然,那里有点差强人意.
now I know it's not perfect.
迈克:差强人意!!??爸爸,那个地方有帮派和吸毒者,那里名声很臭.
Mike: Not pefect!!??Dad, that place has gang members and drug addicts and that's the
honours program
贾森:他说的有道理,玛吉,那里可真不怎么样.
Jason: He does have a point Maggie, that place can be real rough.
玛吉:贾森…
Maggie: Jason...
贾森:他还是到那里待上一段时间吧.
Jason: Well he's just gonna have to suck it up.
玛吉:迈克,我们都很同情卢克,
Maggie: Mike, we all feel sorry for Luke, but life isn't always fair.
但生活本来就是不公平的.有些事我们也无能为力.
There are some things we can't fix.
贾森:迈克,我会尽快把他从帕顿霍尔接出来,
Jason: I'll get him out of Paton Hall and into a foster home as soon as
送到收养他的人家里去.我们只能这么做了.
I can Mike.That's the best we can do.
迈克:卢克!嘿,你要记住我家里的人.
Mike: Luke!Hey, you remember my folks.
贾森:嗨,卢克.
Jason: Hi Luke.
迈克:呃…听我说卢克,我们刚刚商量过了,现在跟你谈一谈.呃…爸爸.
Mike: Uhh...Listen Luke, we've bee talking things over and well just to lay it
out there for you.Uhh...Dad
贾森:好的,卢克.迈克想说的是我们完全理解你的处境,
Jason: Well Luke, what Mike's trying to say is that we completely understand
也很同情你,所以,呃…玛吉.
your situation and we sympathize and so uh... Maggie.
玛吉:你可以住在我们家!!
Maggie: You can stay with us!!
卡罗尔:如果你要住进我房间的话,就要记住一些基本规定.
Carol: Now if you are going to be using my room for awhile, you need to know some of the ground rules.
第一,不准本碰我的绒毛玩具.
Number one, don't let Ben touch fluffy things.
第二,不准本碰其他东西.
Number two, don't let Ben touch anything else.
卢克:记住了.
Luke: Got it.
卡罗尔:那好.再说衣柜.
Carol: Ok, now the closet.
你可以用这一半,但要保证不能把你的衣服跟我的弄混了.
You can use this half but make sure your clothes don't crowd mine.
我想不用告诉你亚麻衣料是很容易弄皱的.
I'm sure I don't have to tell you how easily linen wrinkles.
卢克:我懂这个道理!所以我穿上一件后,
Luke: It's a stinking crime!
一年的时间都穿它.
That's why I pick one look and stick with it all year long.
卡罗尔:对不起,我没想到.那你冬天怎么过啊?
Carol: I'm sorry, I wasn't thinking.How do you stay warm in the winter?
卢克:哦,在牙买加不成问题.
Luke: Oh, no problem in Jamaica man.
卡罗尔:牙买加?
Carol: Jamaica?
卢克:对啊,我生长在那里,
Luke: Yeah I grew up there, I go back there every winter,
每年冬天我就回去.我在伐木场当过火夫.
I use to work as a cook at a plantation.
卡罗尔:那是个苦差事吧.
Carol: That must be a tough job.
卢克:这么说吧,要为68个靠力气吃饭的男人做蛋白椰丝蛋糕,
Luke: All I can say is when you got to cook macaroons for 68 sweaty men
你就得学会照看自己的椰子.
with machetes you better learn to watch your coconuts.
本:嘿,卢克!
Ben: Hey Luke!Mike and I thought you might need some extra clothes while
迈克和我认为你也许需要这些衣服.
you're here.
卢克:牛仔, T-恤,还有胸罩??
Luke: Jeans, T-shirts and a bra??
本:实际上,这是卡罗尔的,妈妈刚洗过的.
Ben: Actually this is Carol's, mom just washed it.
卡罗尔:算了吧,我还是重新洗洗吧.
Carol: Great, now it needs to be washed again.
本:她要走吗?
Ben: She's gone?
卢克:对,怎么了?
Luke: Yeah why?
本:哦,毛绒玩具…
Ben: Awww.Fluffy
卢克:她不愿意你这样.
Luke: I don't think she wants you doing that.
本:我知道,所以我才这么做.
Ben: I know, that's why I do it.
我不知道她怎么知道的,但这会气疯她的.
I don't know how she knows, but it drives her nuts.
嘿,宝贝,我让你闻闻本叔叔的腋窝.有一大堆女生的东西,你能谁安稳吗?
Hey Flufster, it's time to smell uncle Benny's armpit.How can you sleep in here
with all this girly stuff
卢克:有张床,我就知足了.
Luke: I'm happy to have a bed at all,
我以前可是睡储藏室和电影院的.
I'm use to sleeping in storerooms and movie theatres.
本:电影院!!??那不是很贵吗??
Ben: Movie theatres!!??Doesn't that get expensive??
卢克:偷摸进去不就得了.
Luke: Not if you sneak in.
本:偷摸进去??
Ben: Sneak in??
卢克:对啊.我有一套拿手的方法,
Luke: Yup, I've got a surefire system where the theatre manager ushers me in,
能让影院经理把我领进去,还要把着门称呼我"先生"呢.
holds the door open and calls me sir.
本:真的!?卢克,我们纯洁的友谊从就要现在开始了.
Ben: Really!?Luke this could be the beginning of a beautiful friendship.
贾森:迈克!!嘿,迈克!!
Jason: Mike!!Hey Mike!!
卡罗尔:爸爸,每个周六,
Carol: Dad, every Saturday you come out here and yell for Mike to come
你都出来把迈克喊出来给你洗车,可结果都是你自己洗.
out and wash the car and you end up washing it yourself.
很明显,喊他是浪费时间.
Obviously yelling is a waste of time.
贾森:很好,那你来洗车吧.
Jason: Fine, you wash the car.
卡罗尔:迈克!!迈克!!
Carol: Mike!!!Mike!!!!
卢克:出什么事了??
Luke: Is something wrong??
贾森:只是叫迈克来洗车.
Jason: Just trying to get Mike to wash the car.
卢克:我来洗吧.
Luke: I'll do it.
卡罗尔:哦,很好,洗车有着落了.
Carol: Oh well, there, that's resolved.
贾森:哦,不,迈克会来洗的.这活很累.
Jason: No No, Mike should do it, it's a big job.
卢克:小菜一碟.我帮飞行员洗过飞机.
Luke: Not for me, I use to wash airplanes for barnstormers,
我就是在机场旁边长大的.
I grew up next to an airfield.
贾森:曼哈顿的飞行员?
Jason: Barnstormers in Manhattan?
卢克:是南达科他州的,号称"金色雄鹰".
Luke: South Dakota, the golden eagles.
我记得一次过生日,他们带我上天,
I remember one time for my birthday,
一个劲儿的转圈,直到把午饭都吐出来.
they took me up with them and spun me around until I lost my lunch.
天啊,我太爱那帮人了.
God I love those guys.
贾森:怪不得你要经常洗飞机呢.
Jason: No wonder the planes needed so much washing.
不行,卢克,
No Luke listen, put that down this is Mike's job, he will do it,
放下,那是迈克的活儿.他会洗的.
it's been Mike's job for 11 years and I want to live long enough just
我都喊他洗车喊了11年了,我一定要在有生一年看到他洗一次.
to see him do it once.
迈克!!迈克!!
Mike!!!Mike!!!
迈克:嘿,卢克!嘿,嘿,嘿!!你在这里干嘛呢!!??
Mike: Hey Luke!Hey hey hey!!What the heck are you doing!!??
卢克:洗你爸爸的车呢.
Luke: I'm washing your dad's car.
迈克:别,卢克.别因为是爸爸叫你,你就干这些杂活.
Mike: No Luke, you don't have to do chores, just cause my dad asks you to.
卢克:哦,他没让我干.我是自愿的.
Luke: Well he didn't ask me, I just volunteered.
迈克:你自愿的!!??卢克,别,别.
Mike: You volunteered!!??Luke, no no no.
也许你可以在城里的街道上这么干,但这是郊区,
Yes maybe that's the way you do it on the streets,
没人帮别人干活的.
but this is suburbia nobody does anything for anybody.
卢克:可他烦着呢,老在吆喝你.
Luke: Well he was upset, he was yelling!
迈克:不怕他吆喝!相信我吧,
Mike: Yelling is nothing!
你不用担心我爸爸,
Believe me, you don't have to worry about my dad until his nostrils flare
除非他气的鼻孔冒烟,
and that view over his left eye brow starts to throb,
太阳穴上的血管鼓起来.那时他就像佛莱笛房肆舾穸歉瞿跻谎卑芑怠?
after that he makes Freddy Kruger look like a guy with press on nails.
贾森:这实在是太不像话了.这是你的活儿,
Jason: This is really reprehensible, this is your job,
他是客人,而你…老天啊!!
this is your guest and that is... Holy smokes!!
洗的真干净.
We got White one.
迈克:想让我接着干吗?
Mike: You want me to take over dad?
贾森:不!
Jason: No!
玛吉:别逗了.你在一个牧场干过吗?
Maggie: No kidding you use to work on a dude ranch?
卢克:要为68个与套索打交道的壮汉做饭的话,
Luke: When you cook for 68 burly men with lassos you learn to watch your
一定要照看好自己的饼干.
biscuits.
玛吉:真怪,我发誓那里放着一瓶酒来着.
Maggie: That's funny I could have sworn there was a bottle of wine in there.
一定是贾森喝了.没关系,家里酒有的是.
Oh Jason must have finished it.It's ok there's plenty more.
卢克:喔,这么多酒.
Luke: Wow, that's a lot of wine.
玛吉:是的,贾森开始收藏了.他非常喜欢酒.
Maggie: Yeah, Jason started collecting, he really likes his wine.
克里西:喂,卢克,我给你介绍个朋友,芭比!
Chrissy: Yo!Luke, I want to introduce you to a friend.Barbie!
卢克:哦,很高兴认识你,芭比.她姓什么?
Luke: Well, pleased to meet you Barbie, does she have a last name?
克里西:多尔!她想邀请你去"圆梦小屋"喝茶.
Chrissy: Doll!She wants to invite you over to her dream house for tea.
卢克:我从不拒绝一个漂亮女士的邀请.
Luke: Well, I never turn donw an invitation from a beautiful woman.
克里西:她有男朋友了.但我可以把他塞到抽屉里.
Chrissy: She's got a boyfriend.But I can stuff them into drawer.
贾森:嘿,迈克.我一个文件夹不见了,里面放着给卢克找收养人的秘密文件.你见到了吗?
Jason:  Hey Mike I had a folder in there of confidential applications for Luke's foster family, have you seen it?
迈克:呃,没有…我没见,爸爸.我什么也不知道.
Mike: Uhh..no...I haven't seen it dad I don't know anything about it.
我一直坐在这里看比赛来着.
I was just sitting here watching the game on TV.
贾森:打开电视看会效果不更好吗?
Jason: Wouldn't it be better if the se were on?
迈克:呃,不.电视画面黑了.
Mike: Uh no.The game was blacked out.
贾森:文件夹.
Jason: Folder.
迈克:好吧.不过事先声明,我没看一眼.爸爸,别把卢克交给布鲁克林的那对夫妇收养.
Mike: Ok, but dad just for the record, I didn't look at a thing, but forget about that couple from Brooklyn.
我不希望让那些老态龙钟的人来收养卢克.
I don't want Luke being raised by people who drag their knuckles on the ground.
贾森:迈克.
Jason: Mike.
迈克:爸爸,对不起,
Mike: Dad, I'm sorry but Luke's just had a tough life and I want to make
但卢克过的够苦的了.我希望保证他能去关心他的人家.
sure he's around people that are about him.
贾森:我知道.
Jason: I know that.
迈克:能生活在好的社区里,上好的学校,
Mike: In a good neigbourhood with a good school and room of his own,
有自己的房间,有独立大门,还有卫星电视.
private entrance and satellite dish.
贾森:我太傻了.我一直在找具有爱心和高尚品德的人家呢.看来我应该找一个有放映厅和健身房的人家.
Jason: Silly me, all this time I've been looking for a stable loving family
with high morale character,
when I should have been looking for someone with a video arcade and a
weight room.
迈克:你终于上路了.
Mike: Now you're talking.
卡罗尔:谢谢让我在家里洗衣服.
Carol: Thanks for letting me do my laundry here mom.
学校洗衣房都快成闹哄哄的菜市场了.
The laundry room in the dorm has become a real meat market pick up place.
玛吉:那别人怎么洗衣服的?
Maggie: How does anyone get their wash done?
卡罗尔:别问我,还没轮到我洗呢!
Carol: Don't ask me, I'm still on the waiting list!
玛吉:呃…宝贝,能把垃圾拿出去吗?
Maggie: Uhh...Sweetheart will you take out the trash?
克里西:没问题!
Chrissy: No problem!
贾森:嘿,谁看到卢克了?那辆旅行车快脏死了.
Jason: Hey anybody seen Luke?That station wagon is kind of looking grungy.
玛吉:他和迈克到外边去物色收养人家去了.
Maggie: He went out with Mike to check out neighbourhoods for foster homes.
我不知道他们去哪了,可迈克说过什么老态龙钟的话.
I odn't know where they went but Mike said something about knuckles dragging.
贾森:哦,去布鲁克林了.
Jason: Oh, Brooklyn.Got to hand it to Mike though,
我把这事交代给迈克了.给卢克找好人家的事,他确实很上心.
he's really serious about finding Luke a good home.
玛吉:我发现,自从把卢克带来后,
Maggie: Well I know ever since he brought Luke here, he's been mature,
他变的成熟,负责和关心人了.
responsible, caring.
贾森:让你有点不适应,是吗?
Jason: Kind of gives you the creeps doesn't it?
玛吉:你总是懂我的心思.
Maggie: You know this is too much,
我记得放了一瓶酒在这里啊.
I know I put a bottle of wine in there.
贾森:酒柜里有的是啊.
Jason: There's more in the cabinet.
玛吉:你肯定?
Maggie: Wanna bet?
贾森:不可能的事啊.
Jason: That's impossible, the last time I looked there were fifteen bottles
上次我还看到那里有15瓶呢.
in there.
克里西:各位,各位,
Chrissy: People, people, people.
各位,我给你说过多少次要回收废品啊?
How many times do I have to tell you about recycling?
玛吉:安静,宝贝.
Maggie: In a minute honey.
克里西:可是妈妈,有人把玻璃扔到一般垃圾里了.
Chrissy: Mom, look somebody put glass into regular garbage.
玛吉:贾森,是酒瓶.
Maggie: Jason, the wine bottles.
贾森:谁干的?
Jason: Who could have?
玛吉:哦,天啊!
Maggie: Oh my god!
贾森:难以置信.
Jason: I can't believe it.
玛吉:是的,太不可思意了.
Maggie: Me neither, it's incredible.
克里西:嘿,有什么大惊小怪的,不过是瓶子嘛,我把它们拣出来.
Chrissy: Hey get a grip, there just bottles.I'll sort them myself.
玛吉:做吧,宝贝.
Maggie: You do that honey.
贾森:我们先不急着做什么结论,
Jason: Well let's not jump to any conclusions here,
还不能肯定就是卢克干的.
we don't know for sure that it was Luke.
卡罗尔:卢克!!?他不会干这个的.
Carol: Luke!!?He couldn't have done it.
玛吉:我同意.他是个负责的孩子.
Maggie: I agree, he's a responsible kid.
毕竟,他整个童年都在为一个牧场煮饭.
After all he spent his entire childhood cooking for a dude ranch.
贾森:不,他没有.他整个童年是与飞行员一起度过的.
Jason: No he didn't.He spent his childhood hanging out with barnstormers.
玛吉:飞行员?
Maggie: Barnstormers?
贾森:金色雄鹰.他们让他在天上都吐了.他喜欢那帮人.
Jason: The Golden Eagles.They use to make him throw up, he loved those guys.
卡罗尔:你们俩听清楚了吗?飞行员!??
Carol: Will you two listen to yourselves?Barnstormers!??Dude Ranch!??
牧场!??我说,你们这么容易受骗啊?
I mean how gullible can you be?
玛吉:你应该知道真实的故事吧.
Maggie: I suppose you know the real story.
卡罗尔:是的.他在牙买加的农场里跟一帮壮汉和椰子树一起长大.
Carol: Yes, he grew up on a plantation in Jamaica with big guys and coconuts.
那个撒谎的小狗偷了你们的酒.
That lying pig dog stole your wine.
本:就这样.卢克说过只要镇静就啥事没有的.
Ben: This is it, Luke said nothing could go wrong as long as I stayed calm.
好了,捡一张票根,别让人发觉.好了,5号放映厅,免费电影.
Ok pick up a ticket stub without drawing attention to yourself.Ok theatre 5, you're home free.
门卫:站住,你这个小滑头.
Guard: Hold it there you little nose wipe.
本:红色警报,保持镇静,给他看票根,跟他看票根!
Ben: Red alert, damage control, show him the stub.Show him the stub!
呃,有事吗?先生.呃,我刚从5号放映厅里出来,我的钱包掉那里了.
Uhh excuse me sir, umm I just came out of theatre 5 and I left my wallet in there.
门卫:你的钱包!??
Guard: Your wallet!??
本:一定是我起身给那些修女让座的时候从口袋里滑出来了.
Ben: Yeah it must have slipped out of my pocket when I stood up to let those nuns take their seats.
门卫:修女也来看吗!!?
Guard: There were nuns watching "When Stewardesses go Bad"!!?
本:他们提前退场了.
Ben: Well they left early.
如果你让我进去,我找到钱包后会在3点15分,
If you just let me go in,
下一场开演前出来.
I'll grab my wallet and I'll be out of there before the next show at 3:15.
门卫:好吧,但要快进快出.
Guard: Ok, but go straight in and come straight out.
本:是,先生.谢谢你先生.
Ben: Yes sir, thank you sir.Touch down.
成功了.现在直接进放映厅,片刻也不停留.
Now go directly into the theatre stopping for nothing.
门卫:找到你的钱包了吗?
Guard: Found your wallet I see?
本:呃,是的…这个是我常用的钱包,那个是我的幸运钱包.
Ben: Uhh Yeah..Well this is just my regular wallet, that was my lucky wallet.
门卫:啊…
Guard: Oh....
本:好主意.他买我的帐了.
Ben: Good thinking, he's buying it.
迈克:妈妈,爸爸,郑重声明,在布鲁克林每个人都挺直腰杆走路.
Mike: Mom, Dad, Just for the record everyone in Brooklyn walked upright.
卢克:那里还有大公园,看这是迈克给我买的.
Luke: There was even this great park and look at what Mike bought me?
迈克:好了,各位,看看吧,把球抛给爸爸.
Mike: Ok guys, check this out, Luke throw it to dad.
迈克:你相信吗,爸爸?
Mike: Can you believe that dad??
在此之前,他从没玩过一次橄榄球.一位橄榄球明星诞生了.
Before this morning he never threw a spiral in his life.Dan Marino watch out!
贾森:那太好了.卢克,
Jason: Alright that's good.
你能先上楼去洗手吗?快吃饭了.
Luke why don't you go upstairs and wash for dinner ok??
卢克:好的,西沃医生.
Luke: Sure, Doctor Seaver.
迈克:看见了吗,啊…他很棒,对不对,爸爸?
Mike: See ya.Aww...Is he a great kid or what huh dad?
贾森:是的,是的.不过,呃,卢克出了点事,我想我们不能给他找领养人了.
Jason: Yeah Yeah, but umm something's happened with Luke and we don't think we will be able to find him a foster home.
迈克:什么!!?
Mike: What!!?
玛吉:而且我们认为他不能再住我们家了.
Maggie: And we don't think he should stay in our home either.
迈克:你们俩在说什么啊!??
Mike: What are you guys talking about!??
玛吉:是这样的,我们在垃圾堆里发现了许多空酒瓶.
Maggie: Well we found a lot of empty wine bottles in the trash and we
而我们谁也没喝酒.
know neither of us drank them.
迈克:你们认为是卢克喝的!?
Mike: You don't think Luke drank them!?
贾森:他需要的帮助超出了我们的能力,
Jason: He needs more help then we can give him,
他应该到戒酒中心去.
he should be in an alcohol treatment program.
玛吉:我们不得不为本和克里西着想.不管怎么样,
Maggie: And we have to think about Ben and Chrissy.
卢克会影响他们的.
Like her or not, Luke will influence on them.
迈克:对不起,我不敢苟同.
Mike: I'm sorry, I'm not bet this, I mean Luke, if Luke try alcohol,
如果卢克真的喝酒了,他应该整天醉醺醺的,
he would be plastered all the time.
可你们看他醉过吗?甚至亲眼见他喝了吗?
Have you ever seen him drunk??Or even hung over!!?
玛吉:那到没有.
Maggie: Well no.
迈克:我也没有.你们谁闻到他嘴里有酒气吗?
Mike: Well neither have I.Have you ever smelled alcohol in his breath?
贾森:没有,不过呃…我还没有找到答案而已,迈克.
Jason: No, but uhh umm...Look I don't have all the answers either Mike.
迈克:再说了,咱家哪个孩子受到不良影响了.
Mike: Show me one kid in this family that he's had a bad influence on.
男人:这个小滑头说他住在这里.
Man: This nose wipe claims to live here.
他逃票溜进马萨皮卡多功能剧院的时候被我们抓住了.
We caught him sneaking into the Masapika Multiplex.
玛吉:本西维尔,你从哪里学来的?
Maggie: Ben Seaver where did you get an idea like that?
本:打死我也不说.
Ben: Nothing can make me talk.
玛吉:小伙子!
Maggie: Young man!
本:卢克教我的.
Ben: It was Luke.
贾森:把他交给我们吧,阁下.
Jason: It's alright we will take it from here, your majesty.
迈克:嘿,卢克,你干什么呢?
Mike: Hey Luke, what are you doing?
卢克:哦,收拾行李呢.
Luke: Oh, packing, I got the picture that my lease was up so I'm taking 2
看来,我要离开了,所以我拿了两双袜子和一条内裤.
pairs of socks and 1 pair of underwear.
我可以开走那个橄榄球吗?
Mind if I keep the football?
贾森:卢克,我们得把话说清楚.
Jason: Luke we have to clear something up.
卢克:好吧,球我不拿了.
Luke: Fine, I'll leave the football.
贾森:不,我说的不是这个.我们在垃圾堆里发现了一些空酒瓶.
Jason: No that's not it, we found some empty wine bottles in the trash.
卢克:怎么了?
Luke: So?
玛吉:卢克,我们想帮你,我们知道你喝酒.
Maggie: Luke we want to help, we know you're drinking.
卢克:我!!??我不会碰那中毒药的!!
Luke:Me!!??I wouldn't touch that poison!!
玛吉:我很想相信你,但飞行员和饼干是怎么回事?
Maggie: I'd like to believe you but between barstorming and biscuits.
我们怎么知道你说的是不是真话呢?
How are we suppose ot know when you're telling the truth?
卢克:我说什么都无所谓.你们已经先入为主了.
Luke: Doesn't matter what I say, you guys have your minds all made up.
迈克:不是所有人.好的,
Mike: Not all of us,
只要你告诉我你没动那些酒,我就相信你.
alright you just tell me you didn't take that wine and I'll believe you.
卢克,告诉我.
Luke tell me.
卢克:我要走了.
Luke: I'm out of here.
迈克:哦卢克.
Mike: Oh, Luke.
贾森:等一下.有需要帮助.有个帮助青少年戒酒的地方.
Jason: Wait a second, You need help, there are programs for teens who drink.
卢克:那就去找个喝酒的少年吧.
Luke: So go find a teen who drinks.
迈克:卢克,你不知道喝酒对你有多大的危害!!?你知不知道酒精会危害你的身体器官!??
Mike: Luke, don't you know how bad that stuff is for you!!?Do you have any idea what alcohol does to your internal organs!??
你的肝,心,还有其他所有的内脏.我说兄弟,你知不知道酗酒会杀了你!!??
You liver, your heart and whatever else is in there.Come on man, don't you know that booze can kill you!!??
卢克:别说了.我知道的酗酒的害处不比你知道的少.
Luke: Leave me alone, you can't tell me anything about booze I don't know.
它会让你迟钝,让你生病,
It makes you stupid, it makes you sick, it makes you forget,
让你健忘,让你对人怀恨在心,让你害怕夜里回家.
makes you hate people, makes you afraid to come home at night.
贾森:什么!!?
Jason: What!!?
卢克:让你害怕提问题或出动静.就算拿一杯水,
Luke: Makes you afraid to ask a question or make a noise.
不管做什么都会让一个醉酒的人大发雷霆.
Get a glass of water, do anything will make a man mad when he's drunk.
迈克:谁喝醉了!!?这里没人喝酒.
Mike: Who's drunk!!?Nobody here is drunk.
贾森:不,他不是在说我们,迈克.是不是,
Jason: No, he's not talking about us Mike, are you Luke hmm?Who gets drunk?
卢克?谁酗酒?你父亲?
Your father?
卢克:我两岁的时候他就走了.
Luke: He left when I was 2.
贾森:那你怕谁喝醉酒?
Jason: Who are you afraid of when they drink?
卢克:我继父.刚开始的时候我喜欢他.他清醒时很和气,
Luke: My step father, I liked him at first, he as fine when he was sober,
就像你.有一次,他还给我买了一个冰激凌.
like you.He even bought me an ice cream once.
可只要喝上几杯酒,他就像换了一个人一样.
But boy when he had a few belts in him, he was a different guy.
脾气暴躁,一碰就着.
Mean, anything would set him off.
贾森:他打你吗?
Jason: Did he beat you?
卢克:是的.我妈试图阻止他,
Luke: Yeah, mom tried to stop him, but he beat her too.
但他连妈也打.我妈死后,他整天就知道喝酒.
After she died, he started drinking all the time.
他不在意任何伤害我.一天晚上,
He didn't care how much he hurt me,
他拿着一个棒球棒追着我打.
one night he came after me with a baseball bat.
如果不跑,他早打死我了.
If I hadn't run, he would have killed me.
玛吉:哦,天哪!
Maggie: Oh my god!
卢克:我要说这都是酒害了他.谁都摆脱不了.
Luke: I tell you it's the liquor that does it to him,
酒是穿肠毒药.
it does it to everybody, its poison!!
贾森:你不想悲剧重演,是吗?
Jason: You didn't want that to happen again did you?
卢克:对!!
Luke: No!!
贾森:你拿了我们的酒?
Jason: You took our wine?
卢克:是的!!
Luke: YES!!
贾森:但你没喝是吗?
Jason: But you didn't drink it??
卢克:我倒到下水道里了!!!一滴都没剩!!!
Luke: I poured it down the drain!!!Every damn drop of it!!!
贾森:因为你不希望谁像你一样受到伤害.
Jason: Cause you didn't want anyone to get hurt like you got hurt.
玛吉:没关系的,一切都会好起来的.
Maggie: It's alright, everything going to be alright.
迈克:那么卢克认为…
Mike: So Luke Thought.
贾森:认为喝酒会让我像他继父一样.
Jason: Thought that drinking would turn me into his step father.
迈克:哦,卢克,一切都会好的,
Mike: Oh hey Luke, it's gonna be alright buddy.
兄弟.我爸爸偶尔会小饮一杯,可他从不失态的.
My dad has a glass of wine every now and then but he never loses control.
卢克:那你为什么说他发脾气的时候比佛莱笛克留格尔那个魔王还凶呢?
Luke: Why'd you say when he was mad, he was worse than Freddy Kruger!??
迈克:呃,我开玩笑的.他从不伤害人的.
Mike: Uhhh, I was kidding, no he never hurt anybody.
贾森:你也许难以相信,但比如这里.
Jason: You might find this hard to believe but there are places you will
有些地方会让你感觉安全的,知道吗?比如这里.
be safe you know?Here for instance.
卢克:你是说不赶我走了!!?
Luke: You mean you aren't kicking me out!!?
玛吉:你可以跟我们一起生活,直到找到一个好家.
Maggie: You can stay with us for as long as it takes to find a good
但我们需要互相信任,对吗?
home but we need to trust each other ok?
卢克:对.
Luke: Ok.
贾森:别编造飞行员和椰子树这样的瞎话了.
Jason: No more lies about barnstormers and coconuts.
玛吉:对,你不用靠编故事来讨人喜欢.
Maggie: Right, you don't need to tell stories in this house to be liked.
本:妈妈,爸爸,
Ben: Mom, Dad, I want to come clean with the truth.
我要澄清一个事实.我刚才是被一帮外星人绑架了.
I was taken hostage by a group of space aliens,
他们说如果不帮他们溜进电影院,他们就把长岛给炸了.
they said if I didn't help them sneak into the movies,
00:22:41,000
they would blow up Long Island.